12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

I have been working professionally as a software developer, technical lead and solution architect since 2003. I am based in the Philippines. I have a wide variety of experience with different languages, frameworks and databases, primarily Java, JavaScript and Python, though I am very open to learning new technologies. I can work well in a team setting, in a leadership role, or as a solo developer. I communicate well, I learn quickly, and I always strive for excellence in my work. I am available for consulting opportunities. I prefer remote work.

Overview

| 2019 | BodiesApp.com - Technical Consultant | |
|------------------------|---|--|
| 2016-2019 | <u>Maroon Studios</u> - Solution Architect and Technical Consultant lead | |
| 2016-2019 | <u>Healthblocks</u> - Solution Architect and Technical Consultant lead | |
| 2016-2019 | Various freelance projects | |
| 2003-2015 | Azeus Systems Limited Philippines - Senior full stack developer and technical lead | |
| 2001 | University of the Philippines Diliman - Graduated BS Electronics and Communcations Engineering | |
| Domains | Web services, Government projects, Social care, Finance, Healthcare, Blockchain | |
| Specialization | Security, Performance, Accessibility, Systems Integration, API Development, Data Analytics, Reporting, Mobile (iOS and Android) | |
| Languages | Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, C++, HTML, CSS | |
| Frameworks | Django, Flask, Laravel, React-Native, jQuery, Spring, Wordpress | |
| Databases | SQL, Oracle, MarkLogic NoSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JDBC, ODBC | |
| OSes and Webservers | Windows, Linux, MacOS, Apache Web Server, Nginx, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Application Server, Jboss | |
| Services | Amazon Web Services, Google Compute Engine, Alicloud | |
| Standards | Accessibility (WCAG), Infosec (ISO27001), HK Gov (HK OGCIO), UK Gov (UK Data Protection Act) | |

12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

Career Details

2019

- BodiesApp.com Technical Consultant
- Consulting on development of a multi-tier system including mobile clients, web platform and API backends
- Working with globally distributed development and testing teams

2016 to 2019

- Maroon Studios Solution Architect and Technical Consultant
- Healthblocks Solution Architect and Technical Consultant
- Various small freelance projects

Technologies and Frameworks used:

- Node.JS + Express
- MarkLogic NoSQL
- PHP + Laravel Web Framework
- Python + Django
- Python + Flask
- Multichain
- React Native
- WordPress customisation, themes, and plugins
- Amazon Web Services (AWS) setup and deployment
- Alicloud setup and deployment
- Blockchain (Multichain and Ethereum based)

Notable Projects:

- AmberTime Coin blockchain wallet and services platform
- Ticket2Me.net online ticketing platform

2003 to 2015

Azeus Systems Limited Philippines - Technical Lead and Full Stack Developer

Project Involvement

- Major involvement in 12 projects for various departments of the Hong Kong Government, including the HK Police Force, Department of Justice, Customs and Excise Department, Social Welfare Department
- Major involvement in 3 projects for the London Borough of Camden
- Major involvement in 3 software products developed in-house
 - Coral Presenter (Powerpoint to Flash Conversion tool)

12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

- Azeus Convene (Corporate meeting platform)
- AzeusCare (Social Care System targeted primarily at the UK government bodies)
- Technical consultation work in many other projects within the company
- Projects within the company are certified with Capability Maturity Model Integration (CMMI) level 5 compliance

Roles and Responsibilities

- System Developer (from Jan 2003 onwards)
 - Coding/implementation of client-side forms-based programs, web-based systems, system reports, interfaces to third-party systems and other programs
 - System deployment and troubleshooting, diagnotics and resolution of problems in live systems
- Technical Lead (from Oct 2005 onwards)
 - Lead developer for multiple project teams ranging in size from 4-50 software developers and testers
 - Responsible for system architecture and framework design and implementation
 - Provided support for coordination work, task management and allocation for the development team
 - Conducted mentoring, code reviews and performance reviews of junior developers
 - Conducted risk management activities, including assessment of technical risks and evaluation of technical options
 - Conducted assessment and tuning of system performance problems, both during development and in live systems. This includes both application server performance and database-level (SQL) performance
 - Responsible for high-level supervision of development cycle, including ensuring efficient build and deployment processes
 - Responsible for managing security risks in the system, including making sure developers are aware of
 security-related best practices and adequate framework support is provided to minimize security-related
 problems. Includes preparation and coordination activities to ensure system compliance with 3rd-party
 security audits
 - Responsible for ensuring system compliance with various standards as required by the client systems, including but not limited to:
 - Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) for accessibility concerns
 - ISO27001 Information Security Management
 - IT Standards of the HK Office of the Government Chief Information Officer (HK OGCIO)
 - UK Data Protection Act

Other roles

- System Analyst (from Oct 2005 onwards): Design and review of implementation of various client requirements; writing functional specifications and database design; on-site consultations with clients and technology partners to discuss requirements and iterate on implementation details. On-site locations include London (United Kingdom) and Hong Kong
- Presales Consultatn (from Apr 2008 onwards): Responsible for drafting technical replies to client tender requirements for presales purposes and consulting on costing and estimation concerns
- In-House Organisation Trainer (from May 2004 onwards): Prepared organizational training materials and conducted training sessions for new hires on the following topics: SQL, Oracle PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, JSP, Java Servlets, Oracle Forms and Reports
- Skills, Programming Languages, and Tools used

12-B Patrick St., Pleasantview Subdivision, Tandang Sora, Quezon City +63917 8515609 (M) | hello@roytang.net | https://roytang.net | https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang

- Web front-end languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Java, including J2EE, JSP, Java Servlets, Java Applets, Web Services
- Visual C#
- Adobe Flex and ActionScript
- Objective-C for iOS mobile applications
- Android SDK for Android mobile applications
- Python scripting
- Oracle RDBMS usage, administration and management
- Web server platforms: Apache Web Server, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Application Server, Jboss
- Third-party platforms: Liferay CMS, Alfresco CMS
- Legacy systems: Oracle Forms and Reports, Borland Delphi, Powerbuilder 6.5

Other skills (outside of work experience)

• Unity Game Development Framework

Education Attainment and Certifications

| Year | Institution | |
|------|---|---|
| 2001 | College of Engineering, University of the Philippines - Diliman | Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communications Engineering |
| 2004 | PhilNITS | Japan IT Standards Examination (JITSE) Certification |
| 2012 | Oracle Certified Professional | Java SE 6 Programmer |